Finding Aid for Zonta Club of Ann Arbor, Michigan records, 1972-1990
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Zonta Club of Ann Arbor, Michigan records 1972-1990 1987-1990
Zonta Club of Ann Arbor, Michigan.
0.5 linear feet.
93805 Aa 2
Ann Arbor chapter of international women's professional and service organization. Administrative records, newsletters, yearly members booklets, correspondence, and other materials relating to club activities.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
This record group (donor no. 8090 ) was received in 1992 and came through club president Margaret Massialas.
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The record group is open to research.
Zonta is a Sioux Indian word meaning "to band together for a purpose." The creators of Zonta International, a service organization of executive women in business and other professions, wanted the organization to represent such values as honesty, trust and inspiration. Zonta members believe by embracing in friendships and joining efforts and talents with others who are like-minded, they enrich their personal and professional lives. Through club meetings, inter-city functions, work shops, district conferences and international conferences, they also work to improve the status of women throughout the world. The Zonta Club of Ann Arbor, a chapter of Zonta International, was organized by members of the Detroit chapter on March 28, 1924 and was chartered on May 16, 1924 with fifteen members.
The records of the Zonta Club of Ann Arbor cover the period 1972 to 1990, though the bulk of the materials date since 1987. The record group largely concerns the official functions of the Club and the various events that it sponsored. The folders in the record group are arranged alphabetically, with the contents of folders either arranged chronologically or alphabetically.
The folders labeled Administrative, Board Meeting Agenda, Business and Social Meetings, and Treasurer's Reports contain organizational records of the club. Included with these files are such items as the president's conference report, the proposed budget for operations, the report of pledges and contributions, various committee reports, committee announcements, officers reports, and financial credits and disbursements. The Correspondence folder constitutes the largest portion of the collection. Included is correspondence with the Zonta International Headquarters in Chicago, Illinois, with the state (District XV) office, and with other clubs in the area (Area III). Also included is correspondence with other service organizations that Zonta of Ann Arbor financially endorsed or worked with in charity functions.
The Published Meetings file contains a set of booklets which are produced annually with the following topics in each booklet: the Zonta Blessing, Zonta Code, Clubwomens Collect written by Mary Stewart, listing of former Club Presidents, Officers Board Members, Committees, yearly calendar, and roster of members. The Social and Educational file contains notices of upcoming charity, social events, educational seminars and regional and national conferences of Zonta International.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.; Zonta Club of Ann Arbor, Michigan.; Zonta International.
- Organizational records
  - Administrative Files (Box 1)
    )nclude President's Conference Report, 1989 Proposed Budget for Operations, 1988-1990 and Report of Pledges and Contributions)
  - Background Information (Box 1)
    ( includes "Everything You Always Wanted to Know About Zonta")
  - Board Meeting Agenda, June 21, 1988-June 19, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Business and Social Meetings, October 18, 1988-February 27, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence-Incoming File, August 4, 1979-May 30, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence-Outgoing File, January 7, 1989-May 6, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Members of Ann Arbor Zonta Club File (Box 1)
    (include memorials of deceased members; and Membership Committee Report for 1988/89-new members)
  - Newsletter File, June 20, 1986-November / December 1989 (Box 1)
  - Published Meetings: include 50th Anniversary booklet, 1924-1974 and yearly booklets, 1972-1989/90 (Box 1)
  - Social and Educational Events, January 17, 1989-July 13, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Standard Bylaws/ Rules of Procedure (Box 1)
    (include proposed amendments; and job description of club president)
  - Treasurer's Reports, January 10, 1989-May 1, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Record book, ca. 1984-1986 (Box 1)